Guide to the Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2
5583/2
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
74 linear ft.
Records (documents), publications (documents).
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Publications, manuals, policies, and plans issued by a large sample of Fortune 500 corporations and by a variety of organizations, such as professional and trade associations, government agencies, and educational and cultural organizations.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Publications, manuals, policies, and plans issued by a large sample of Fortune 500 corporations and by a variety of organizations, such as professional and trade associations, government agencies, and educational and cultural organizations. The materials issued by corporations include company histories, employee newsletters, employee benefit plans, personnel practice manuals, performance appraisal forms, affirmative action policies, training brochures, job descriptions, and career development programs as well as national trade association documents and recruitment material.
Several economic activities(sectors) are represented in the collection, such as manufacturing, transportation, mining, banking, insurance, utilities, trade, and services. Corporations whose pamphlets are held in the collection include AT&T, Bethlehem Steel, Bell Telephone System, Firestone Tire & Rubber, Ford Motor Co., General Electric, General Foods, General Mills, General Motors, Goodyear Tire & Rubber, Heinz, International Harvester, Johnson & Johnson, Lockheed Aircraft Co., Maytag Co., Metropolitan Life Insurance Co., National Association of Manufacturers, Pennsylvania Railroad Co., Radio Corporation of America (RCA), Standard Oil, Tennessee Valley Authority, Union Carbide, and Westinghouse Electric among numerous other corporations.
SUBJECTS
Names:
A. Kimball Company.; B.F. Goodrich Company.; Civil Service Commission of the City of New York.; Council of Retail Merchants (Ohio); Eli Lilly and Company.; General Electric Company. Erie Works (Erie, PA).; General Electric Company. River Works (Lynn, Mass.); General Electric Company. Pittsfield Works (Pittsfield, Mass.); General Foods Corporation.; General Mills, inc.; General Motors Corporation.; General Motors Corporation. Delco Products Division.; General Petroleum Corporation.; General Shoe Corporation.; General Telephone & Electronics Corporation.; General Telephone Company of California.; General Telephone Company of Indiana.; General Telephone Company of Michigan.; General Telephone Corporation.; Geneva Steel (Firm); Gerber Products Company.; Glass Container Manufacturers Institute.; Glenshaw Glass Company.; Globe Ticket Company.; B.F. Goodrich Company.; Goodyear Atomic Corporation.; Goodyear Tire and Rubber Company.; Grand Union Company.; Graphic Arts Employers of America.; Grumman Aircraft Engineering Corporation.; Guaranty Trust Company of New York.; H.J. Heinz Company.; Hallmark Cards, Inc.; Haloid Company.; Haloid Xerox, Inc.; Harris Trust and Savings Bank.; Harris-Intertype Corp.; Harris-Seybold Company.; Harvard University.; Hawaii Employers Council.; Hawaiian Pineapple Co.; Hercules Incorporated.; Honeywell Inc.; Hotpoint.; University of Hawaii (Honolulu). -- Industrial Relations Center.; Illinois Bell Telephone Company.; Illinois Central Industries.; Illinois Central Railroad Company.; University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign. -- Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations.; Imperial Chemical Industries, ltd.; Imperial Oil Limited.; Industrial Accident Prevention Associations.; Industrial Association of San Francisco.; Industrial Hygiene Council.; Industrial Hygiene Foundation of America.; Ingersoll-Rand Company.; Inland Steel Company.; Institute of Life Insurance (New York, N.Y.); Institute of Management & Labor Relations.; International Business Machines Corporation.; International Nickel Company.; International Paper Company.; John Hancock Mutual Life Insurance Company.; Johns-Manville Corporation.; Johnson & Johnson.; Johnson Wax.; Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation.; Kaiser Steel Corporation.; Kennecott Copper Corporation.; Kimberly-Clark Corporation.; Koppers Company.; Kroger Company.; Leeds and Northrup Company.; Lever Brothers Company.; Libby, McNeill & Libby.; Libby-Owens Company.; Libby-Owens-Ford Glass Company.; Liberty Mutual Insurance Company.; Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company.; Lincoln Electric Company.; Lincoln Telephone & Telegraph Company.; Lockheed Aircraft Corporation.; Lukens Steel Company.; Lumberman's Industrial Relations Committee.; Manufacturers Hanover Trust Company.; Marathon Corporation.; Marathon Oil Company.; Marquette Cement Manufacturing Company.; Marquette University.; Marshall Field & Company.; Maytag Corporation.; McCord Corporation.; McGraw-Hill Book Company.; McGraw-Hill Companies.; McGraw-Hill Publishing Company.; McKesson and Robbins, inc.; McMurray Company.; Mead Corporation.; Mead Johnson & Company.; Merchants and Manufacturers Association.; Merck & Co.; Meredith Publishing Group.; Merrill Lynch, Pierce, Fenner & Beane.; Mesta Machine Company.; Metropolitan Life Insurance Company.; Michigan Bell Telephone Company.; Michigan Central Railroad Company.; Michigan. Civil Rights Commission.; Michigan. Civil Service Commission.; Michigan. Department of Labor.; Michigan. Department of Social Services.; Michigan. Labor Mediation Board.; Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing Company.; Mobil Chemical Company.; Mobil Oil Corporation.; Mobil Overseas Oil Company.; Mobil Research and Development Corporation.; Mohawk Airlines.; Monroe Calculation Machine Company.; Monsanto Chemical Company.; Montgomery Ward.; Motorola, inc.; Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York.; Nash-Kelvinator Corporation.; National Academy of Arbitrators.; National Association of Broadcasters.; National Association of Foremen.; National Association of Furniture Manufacturers.; National Association of Manufacturers (U.S.); National Biscuit Company.; National Broadcasting Company.; National Cash Register Company.; National Coal Association.; National Committee for Full Employment (U.S.); National Consumers' League.; National Council on the Aging.; National Education Association of the United States; National Electrical Manufacturers Association.; National Farmers' Union (U.S.); National Foremen's Institute.; National Industrial Council (U.S.); National Management Association (U.S.); National Metal Trades Association (U.S.); National Restaurant Association (U.S.); National Restaurant Managers Association (U.S.); National Safety Council; National Society of Professional Engineers.; National Steel Corporation.; National Urban League.; New England Electric System.; New England Powers Association.; New England Telephone and Telegraph Company.; New Jersey Bell Telephone Company.; New Jersey Manufacturers Association.; New Jersey. Department of Civil Service.; New York (N.Y.). Department of Personnel.; New York (State). Temporary Commission Against Discrimination.; New York (State). Department of Civil Service.; New York (State). Department of Labor.; New York (State). Public Employment Relations Board.; New York (State). Workmen's Compensation Board.; New York Central Railroad Company.; New York Shipping Association.; New York State Electric and Gas Corporation.; New York Stock Exchange.; New York Telephone Company.; New York Times Company.; North American Aviation, inc.; Northeastern University (Boston, Mass.); Northwest Packers and Growers, inc.; Northwestern Bell Telephone Company.; Nunn-Bush Shoe Company.; Ohio Oil Company.; Ontario Hydro.; Organization Resources Counselors, Inc.; Owens-Corning Fiberglas Corporation.; Owens-Illinois Glass Company.; P.H. Hanes, Knitting Company.; Pacific Gas and Electric Company.; Pacific Power and Light Company.; Penn Central Merger Information Committee.; Penn Central Transportation Company.; Pennsylvania Railroad.; Peoples Gas Light and Coke Company.; Personnel Management Association of New York.; Personnel Management Association of the Northeast.; Personnel Management Association, inc.; Pfizer Inc.; Philadelphia Gas Works.; Philadelphia Rapid Transit Company.; Philadelphia Transportation Company.; Philip Morris and Company.; Phillips Petroleum Company.; Pillsbury Mills, Inc.; Pitney-Bowes, inc.; Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company.; Port of New York Authority.; Potomac Electric Power Company.; Potomac Sand & Gravel.; Procter & Gamble Company.; Prudential Insurance Company of America.; Public Personnel Association.; Public Service Corporation of New Jersey.; Public Service Electric and Gas Company.; State University of New York.; Theo. Hamm Brewing Company.; Thomas Macy & Co.; University of Michigan.; University of Minnesota.; University of Minnesota. Industrial Relations Center.; University of Mississippi.
Subjects:
Adult education; Aeronautics; Agricultural industries; Aluminum industry and trade; Airlines; Aircraft industry; Agricultural machinery; Architectural metal-work; Automobile industry and trade; Arbitration, Industrial; Agricultural chemicals industry; Audio equipment industry; Bituminous materials industry; Building trades; Buildings--Environmental engineering; Banks and banking; Breweries; Baked products industry; Business consultants; Clothing trade; Coal mines and mining; Chemical industry; Compressor industry; Clerks (Retail trade); Computer industry; Cereal products; Consumer protection; Container industry; Credit unions; Clay industries; Cement industries; Copper alloys; Dairy products industry; Detergent industry; Executives--Training of; Electric power transmission; Electronics industries; Food industry and trade; Frozen foods and industry; Footwear industry; Fruit trade; Farm produce--Marketing--Government policy; Finance, Public; Glass container industry; Glass manufacture; Gas extraction; Grain trade; Grocery trade; Gasket industry; Human capital; Hydroelectric power plants; Life insurance.; Iron industry and trade; Property insurance.; Casualty insurance.; Instructional materials industry; Health insurance.; Investment banking; Infant formula industry; Knit good industry; Labor unions; Local transit; Luggage industry; Logging; Medical supplies industry; Medicaid; Motor vehicle industry; Metal trade; Meat industry and trade; Military vehicle industry; Medical instruments and apparatus industry; Management; Measuring instruments; Natural gas pipelines; Notions (Merchandise); Newspaper publishing; Navigation equipment industry; National security; Office management; Office equipment and supplies; Petroleum refineries; Photographic industry; Paper folding (Graphic design); Public utilities; Paper products industry; Political participation; Plastics industry and trade; Pharmaceutical industry; Paint industry and trade; Public administration; Public opinion polls; Paper bag industry; Retail trade; Rug and carpet industry; Railroads; Rubber industry and trade; Railroad equipment industry; Roller bearings; Security systems industry; Service industries; Social security; Shipment of goods; Sanitary supply industry; Soybean industry; Slaughtering and slaughter-houses; Transportation equipment industry.; Telecommunication.; Trucking industry.; Trucks--Design and construction.; Textile industry.; Trade associations.; Tobacco industry.; Universities and colleges.; Vocational education.; Wood products.; Welding equipment industry.; Woolen goods industry.
Form and Genre Terms:
Records (documents); Publications (documents)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related Collections:
5880: Archives Organization File V, Additional Company Documents
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1
5583/3: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3
5583/4: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 4. Corporate and Organizational Publications
5583/5: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 5
5583/6: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 6
5956: Archives Organization File Additional records
CONTAINER LIST
- Box: 68, folder: 1 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Job Corps Facts, Publication (Box 68, Folder 1)
    Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Is There a Job in Your Future?, Publication (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Every girl needs a chance to become somebody, Publication (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Job Corps, Publication (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: Is There a Job in Your Future?, Publication (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: They're Ready, Publication (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: They're Ready, Publication (Box 68, Folder 1)
- Box: 68, folder: 2 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Employment Act of 1946, as Amended, and Related Laws and Rules of the Joint Economic Committee Congree of the United States, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Publications of the Joint Economic Committee Congress of the United States, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
    Januarty 1947-August 1961. Item is in English.
- Box: 68, folder: 3 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Committee Publications and Policies Governing Their Distribution, Publication (Box 68, Folder 3)
    March 2, 1964. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Publications of the Joint Economic Committee Congress of the United States, Publication (Box 68, Folder 3)
    January 1947-April 1962. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Publications of the Joint Economic Committee Congress of the United States, Publication (Box 68, Folder 3)
    January 1947- April 1962. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Committee Publications and Policies Governing their Distribution, Publication (Box 68, Folder 3)
    1947-1964. Item is in English.
- Box: 68, folder: 4 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Financial Reports Folder, Publication (Box 68, Folder 4)
- Box: 68, folder: 5 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Letter Regarding Group Life Insurance, Publication (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: Some Facts About Employment, Publication (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Some Facts About Employment, Publication (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: Synopsis and Qualifications Statement, Publication (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: Revision of Qualification Statements, Publication (Box 68, Folder 5)
    March 12, 1956. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Index of Language Skills, Publication (Box 68, Folder 5)
    August 9, 1957. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Application for Posted Vacancy, Publication (Box 68, Folder 5)
- Box: 68, folder: 6 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Smaller Communities Program, Publication (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: The Mdta and Your Health Manpower Needs, Publication (Box 68, Folder 6)
- Box: 68, folder: 7 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Employment Services for Veterans: Annual Report, Publication (Box 68, Folder 7)
    July 1963-June 1964. Item is in English.
- Box: 68, folder: 8 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: The United States Merchanct Marine: A Brief History, Publication (Box 68, Folder 8)
- Box: 68, folder: 9 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Executive Order: Establishing a Program for Revolving Labor Disputes at Missle and Space Sites, Publication (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Item 2: Industrial Labor Policy, Publication (Box 68, Folder 9)
    August 23, 1961. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Establishing a Program for Resolving Labor Disputes at Missile and Space Sites, Publication (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Item 4: Construction Labor Policy, Publication (Box 68, Folder 9)
    July 17, 1961. Item is in English.
- Box: 68, folder: 10 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: The Missile Site Labor Story, Publication (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Item 2: Analysis of Work Stoppages on U.S. Missile Sites, Publication (Box 68, Folder 10)
    June 1961-May 1962. Item is in English.
- Box: 68, folder: 11 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Report of the Missile Site Public Contracts Advisory Committee to Secretary of Labor, Publication (Box 68, Folder 11)
    August 25, 1961. Item is in English.
- Box: 68, folder: 12 (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Where to go for UN information, Publication (Box 68, Folder 12)
- Box: 68, folder: 13 (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Letter to a Friend, Publication (Box 68, Folder 13)
- Box: 68, folder: 14 (Box 68, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: 1965 Regional Seminar, Publication (Box 68, Folder 14)
- Box: 68, folder: 15 (Box 68, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Your Employment Future with the National Labor Relations Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 15)
  - Item 2: A Career in Labor-Management Relations as a Field Examiner, Publication (Box 68, Folder 15)
- Box: 68, folder: 16 (Box 68, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Repondent's Brief in Support of its Exceptions to the Intermediate Report, Publication (Box 68, Folder 16)
  - Item 2: NLRB Hearings End; Cornell Awaits Decision, Publication (Box 68, Folder 16)
  - Item 3: A Layman's Guide to Basic Law Under the National Labor Relations Act, Publication (Box 68, Folder 16)
- Box: 68, folder: 17 (Box 68, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Announcment of Region 29, Publication (Box 68, Folder 17)
  - Item 2: Jurisdictional Guide, Publication (Box 68, Folder 17)
- Box: 68, folder: 18 (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: The National Labor Relations Board Provides Services for Working Men & Women Employers & Unions (Large & Small), Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 2: Actions for the 70's on: NLRB Reform, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 3: Proposals of Chamber of Commerce of United States for Consideration by Congress in Revision of National Labor Relations (Official Text), Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 4: What you should know about the Regional Offices of the National Labor Relations Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    By Stuart Rothman. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: An Effective Labor Policy for the United States, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    By Sylvester Petro. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: NLRB Selects "25,000,000th Voter", Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    February 19, 1967. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: NLRB Procedures and Economic Policy, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    By Murray Edelman. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Hearing on Philip Ray Rodgers to be a Member of the National Labor Relations Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    June 30, 1958. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Hearing on Nomination of Guy Farmer to be a Member of the National Labor Relations Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    July 9, 1953. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Hearing on Nomination of Boyd Stewart Leedom, of South Dakota, to be a Member of the National Labor Relations Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    February 25, 1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Hearing on Joseph A. Jenkins to be a Member of the National Labor Relations Board and Jerome D. Fenton to be General Counsel of the National Labor Relations Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    February 21, 1957. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: Hearing on Nomination of Boyd Stewart Leedom, of South Dakota, to be a Member of the National Labor Relations Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 13: Hearing on Philip Ray Ridgers to be a Member of the National Labor Relations Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 14: Some Effects of the Separation of Function in the National Labor Relations Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 15: Hearing on Philip Ray Rodgers to be a Member of the National Labor Relations Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 16: Hearing on Nomination of Theophil Carl Kammholz, of Illinois, to be General Counsel of the National Labor Relations Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    January 24, 1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 17: A Practice Lawyer Looks at the Labor Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    April 25, 1957. Item is in English.
  - Item 18: How Lawyers Can Help the Labor Board do a Better Job, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 19: NLRB Realigns Regional Boundaries Between New York City and Buffalo, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    April 21, 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 20: NLRB Appoints Six Trial Examiners, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    April 22, 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 21: Hearing on Robert O. Boyd to be a Member of the National Mediation Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    February 2, 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 22: NLRB Regional Office Created at Indianapolis, Indiana, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    February 16, 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 23: NLRB Realigns Regional Boundaries Between New York City and Buffalo, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 24: NLRB General Counsel Issues Statement og Principles and Instructions to Staff Regarding Force and Violence in Labor Disputes, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    May 31, 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 25: NLRB Appoints Five Trial Examiners, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    February 12, 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 26: Arnold Ordman Sworn in as NLRB General Counsel, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    May 14, 1963. Item is in English.
  - Item 27: NLRB Appoints Five Trial Examiners, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 28: NLRB Appoints Six Trial Examiners, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 29: NLRB Names Ogden Fields as a New Executive Secretary, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    March 4, 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 30: NLRB General Counsel Issues Statement of Principles and Instructions to Staff Regarding Force and Violence in Labor Disputes, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 31: NLRB Regional Office Created at Memphis, Tennessee, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    March 25, 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 32: National Labor Relations Board Appoints Director of Personnel, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    December 9, 1959. Item is in English.
  - Item 33: Hugh Frank Malone Appointed NLRB Regional Attorney at Memphis, Tennessee, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    April 11, 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 34: Bernard L. Balicer Appointed Regional Attorney of NLRB Regional Office at Newark, New Jersey, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    April 7, 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 35: Current Headaches of the Labor Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    September 26, 1957. Item is in English.
  - Item 36: Address of Philip Ray Rodgers, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    September 17, 1954. Item is in English.
  - Item 37: Board Member Joseph Alton Jenkins Names Chief Counsel, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    April 14, 1959. Item is in English.
  - Item 38: NLRB Appoints Sual J. Jafe as Associate Solicitor, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    May 3, 1959. Item is in English.
  - Item 39: NLRB Chairman Frank W. McCulloch, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    May 15, 1962. Item is in English.
  - Item 40: Summary Report Operational Activities Office of the General Counsel National Labor Relations Board, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    July 26, 1961. Item is in English.
  - Item 41: Board Member Rodgers Appoints Chief Counsel and Associates, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 42: George A. Leet Promoted in NLRB Office of the Executive Secretary, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    March 24, 1960. Item is in English.
  - Item 43: William T. Evans Named Special Assistant to General Counsel, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    June 5, 1959. Item is in English.
  - Item 44: Let's Stop Labor Board's Unfair Practices, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 45: Let's Stop Labor Board's Unfair Practices, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Item 46: NLRB Announces Leaflet and Notice Program to Inform Workers of Rights in Voting for Collective Bargaining Representation, Publication (Box 68, Folder 18)
    January 20, 1967. Item is in English.